## **▲** CAREER PROFILE

I'm a person who likes to learn and teach, always learning to use a new programming language, a framework, library or some electronic device that allows me to create useful or simply fun things. I do not consider myself an expert in anything, but if you must learn something to achieve the objectives of the project or improve things for everyone, I will surely put all my effort into learning it well, teaching it to my team and putting it into practice. This is some of my projects <u>below.</u> So, may be we can work together!

# **EXPERIENCES**

### Funder DigData

2019 - Present

This is an entrepreneur project that seeks to facilitate the use of new technologies for better management of information produced in the Dominican Republic. Given the country's need to improve its technology infrastructure in relation to education and production.

### Professor

2018 - Present

CEMAS Fe y Alegría, La Vega, Dom. Rep.

To teach the subjects in: - Programmable Logic Controls (PLC with Arduino) - Development of applications (Nodejs and Reactjs) -Computer Networks. - Build a program of theoretical and laboratory classes. - Supervise students' learning processes and motivate their development of new skills. - To strengthen the collaboration and empathy between work teams in educational projects.

### Professor

2016 - Present

UCATECI, La Vega, Dom. Rep.

To teach the subjects in: - Structured Algorithms with Python. - Digital Electronics and Boolean Algebra with VHDL, FPGA in IceZUM Alhambra and Icestudio. - Build programs of university subjects for laboratory and theoretical classes.

## Software Developer for Big Data Applications

2015 - 2016

AYSCOM celular de servicios SL, Madrid, Spain

Develop an application of grouping and processing of data using distributed systems such as Apache Hadoop and Apache Storm. - Java and JavaScritpt programming language. -Version control systems with GIT. -Software project management and comprehension tool with Apache Maven. - Restful API with Nodejs and Expressjs. - Agile methodologies with

### Sub-contracted Tele-measurement Data Analyst

2012 - 2014

 $\underline{\sf EDENORTE} \ and \ \underline{\sf Electrical} \ \underline{\sf Equipment} \ \underline{\sf Supplier}, \underline{\sf Santiago}, \underline{\sf Dom.} \ \underline{\sf Rep}.$ 

Data analysis for electrical fraud detection using telemetered measurement systems. - Use of advanced Data Analysis Tools. - Supervision of fraud detection technical team, 2 technicians under supervision. - Report of electric frauds for judicial cases - Supervision of infra structure of measurement in field, maintenance of the same. -Creation and identification of statistical models for common fraud.

# **CERTIFICATIONS AND PERSONAL PROJECTS**

Projects, To get general information about certificacions and private project or not-finished projects.

# **DigData Projects**

Digital Register for school grades - I am currently working on a personal project, consisting of a system of management of school grades that works in a distributed manner throughout the territory of the Dominican Republic. For this project I am using React JS and React Native in the front part and in the backend I use Nodejs, Apollo JS, GraphQL, Apache Hadoop as file system, Apache Cassandra as a distributed database system and Apache



# Lizandro J. Ramírez Difo

Software Developer | Big Data | Enthusiastic Data Scientist | IoT | Professor | React | Node | | Python | Java

### ■ lizandro23difo@gmail.com

<u> +1 (809) 451 2557</u>

in linkedin.com/in/lizandro23difo/

github.com/difo23

<u> twitter.com/lizandro23difo</u>

### **EDUCATION**

Master's Degree in Distributed and Embedded Systems Software

Universidad Politécnica de Madrid (UPM) 2014 - 2016

# Degree in Telematics Engineer

Pontificia Universidad Católica Madre y Maestra (PUCMM) 2007 - 2012

Degree Technical for industrial electronics specialty communications

Instituto Politécnico Loyola (IPL) 2003 - 2006

### **LANGUAGES**

Spanish (Native)

English (Professional)

French (Beginner)

# **INTERESTS**

Statistics

1 de 3 18/2/20 10:50 a. m.

Education

Data Science

Nutrition

Lecture

Electronics

Spark with python libraries for data processing.

Digital pattern for town councils - This is another project that I am doing in DigData. It consists of a system of residents' registration for the town councils, the main idea is to gather and facilitate the management of the services of the town hall and maintain statistics of population growth. The technologies and architecture used for this project are similar to the Digital Register project for school grades.

# **Certifications & Courses**

<u>Curso Completo de Python 2019 ¡Desde Cero Hasta Experto!</u> - Udemy -UC-E7MF0WG1 - 2019.5

<u>Data Science with Plotly, NumPy, Matplotlib, and Pandas</u> - UDEMY - UC-A4FCLUN9 - 2019.5

Data Science R Basics - DataCamp - #9597901 - 2019.5

Node JS: De cero a experto - Udemy - UC-IZOREZL3 - 2019.4

<u>Visual Studio Code: Mejora tu velocidad para codificar</u> - Udemy - UC-7GBH40SO - 2019.4

JavaScript Tutorial - SoloLearn - #1024-7718035 - 2018.6

Python 3 Tutorial - SoloLearn - #1073-7718035 - 2018.5

<u>Apache Spark with Scala - Learn Spark from a Big Data Guru</u> - Udemy - UC-GX88UZA0 - 2018.5

<u>Curso en linea Scrum Master +Revolucion agil + Liderar Equipos Scrum</u> - Udemy - UC-HFO8IE1K - 2018.3

React JS + Redux + ES6. Completo ¡De 0 a experto! - Udemy - UC-4YVQT46C - 2018.2

Certificate in University Teaching - UCATECI - 2017.11

<u>Immersion English program for competitiveness (830 Hours)</u> - MESCyT - 2017.11

Certificate in Teacher Qualification - UAPA - 2017.11

# 

Project Manager

Javascript ReactJS ReactNative Redux Webpack Npm/Yarn Git Java MongoDB **Design Patterns** SOLID PRINCIPLES Apache Cassandra Apache Spark GraphQL API REST Big O analysis Node **Funtional Programing** Scala Python Jupiter Python for Data Science R and Rstudio MariaDB Conda SQLite Apache Storm Arduino Raspberry Pi **FPGA** Micro Controlers PLC Apache Pig **Pandas** NumPy MatPloitLib Statistic **Ubuntu Server** Electronics **Networking with Cisco** 

2 de 3 18/2/20 10:50 a. m.